JOHNATHAN HEBERT

CONTACT INFORMATION

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- React.js
- Vue.js
- Angular
- Node.js
- Nest.js
- Blockchain
- Solidity
- Rust

LANGUAGES

English | Native

OVERVIEW

I am a full-stack developer with a broad and versatile coding skill set. I quickly help startups and enterprises with prototypes and ideas by efficiently building those things into reality. My expertise lies in building MVPs, apps, enterprise software, scalable microservices, web crawlers, REST and Socket APIs, infrastructure modeling, AWS, and deployments. I am the go-to guy for any of your development needs.

EXPERIENCE

СТО

Around. Remote | 2020 - 2022

- Developed complete React and React Native applications.
- Designed and developed an event-driven architecture using the Serverless
- Developed a Slack app to interact with users directly (messages with actions, update statuses, and more).

Technologies: Slack App, Amazon Cognito, Amazon DynamoDB, GraphQL, Fastlane, Serverless Framework, AWS Amplify, Serverless, React, React Native

FULL-STACK APP DEVELOPER

Combi-Lift. Remote | 2020 - 2020

- Built the client app in React Native.
- Created the architecture for the server's back-end.
- Provided APIs and libraries for other developers to use.
- Enabled the app to work across all the major mobile operating systems including iOS, Windows, and Android.

Technologies: Windows, iOS, Android, PostgreSQL, TypeScript, Node.js, Firebase, React, React Native

APP DEVELOPER

Friend-Uno. Remote | 2019 - 2020

- Built from scratch an app in React Native in three months.
- Implemented the search functionality by adding Elasticsearch in the back-end.
- Used Firebase and Expo.io for real-time content updates and app deployments.
- Created from scratch the admin portal in React in a period of six weeks with features like different user roles, bulk content uploads using CSV files, a notification panel to send a notification to a particular set of users, and more.

Technologies: Elasticsearch, Expo.io, Express.js, Node.js, Firebase, React, React

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Reservations. Remote | 2017 - 2018

- Worked on features like custom fields and a cash-back system.
- Built the user module from scratch with various roles like consumer, supplier, administrator, and more.
- Constructed the website from scratch with a team of three in React. - Set up the back-end in Node.js for enhancing the SPA speed and SEO.
- Developed an analytics engine for the marketing team to help them understand the marketing ROI.

Technologies: Redis, MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js, React, Spring, Java EE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Headout. Remote | 2015 2017 - Developed a bulk data updater for uploading and updating bulk data (100 GB)
- into the analytics panel of Headout with failsafe and error reporting.
- Implemented full featured audit trails to capture a snapshot of each change made to the required data along with a feature to roll back to any version.
- Designed and built a promotion tool to upload, use, and validate promotions code into campaigns.
- Implemented a campaign editor and scheduler.
- Designed a notification utility that can be used for drafting, scheduling, or executing any kind of notification along with Webhooks for a client's custom implementation.

Technologies: Ruby, TypeScript, Node.js, Angular

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CostXpert AG. Remote | 2013 - 2015

- Created the architecture for the server's back-end.
- Oversaw the UI development using CSS, Bootstrap, and LESS. - Provided APIs and libraries for other developers to use.

Technologies: Express.js, React, MySQL, Node.js

FOUNDING DEVELOPER

Eureka Software Services. Remote | 2012 - 2013 - Created an iPhone app for drivers and passengers to see each other on maps

- in real-time using Objective-C.
- Developed a back-end for Socket-based connectivity. - Added an on-premise caching layer to speed up the API.
- Built and iterated multiple times over the design, UI, and UX of the app.

Technologies: PHP, Node.js, Objective-C

EDUCATION

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Swinburne University of Technology. | 2009 - 2014

GRADUATE DEGREE

Excelsia College. | 2006 - 2009